ELIZABETH STONE

(406) 224-2936 • lizzystone13@gmail.com • Boston, MA linkedin.com/in/its-liz • github.com/liztheshiz • liztheshiz.github.io/portfolio-website

WEB DEVELOPER

Thoughtful developer skilled in workplace relationships and quick grasp of new concepts and skills. Experienced in a wide array of web development technologies like JavaScript, React, cloud deploy architecture, and API development. Strong understanding of big-picture quality and workflow. AWS CP certified.

Skilled in:

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- React
- AWS (CP Certified)
- Git + GitHub

- Node + npm
- MongoDB
- Browser compatibility
- Responsive design
- Bootstrap
- API development
- Accessibility standards
- PostgreSQL + NoSQL

DEV EXPERIENCE

CareerFoundry | Cloud Computing for Web Developers (Remote)

Oct 2022-Feb 2023

- Developed and deployed fully integrated web app on AWS, optimized by AWS standards in computing efficiency, security, and reliability
- Completed AWS training course and passed the AWS CCP exam, receiving CP certification

CareerFoundry | Full-Stack Web Development Certification (Remote)

Apr 2022-Sept 2022

- Developed six web apps from scratch with feedback from industry professionals, including:
 - o Multiple sites written entirely in vanilla HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
 - o Single-page web app built with React and Bootstrap
 - o MongoDB database and Express API for use with two frontend projects
 - o Progressive web app that uses Google OAuth2 for authentication
 - o Native real-time mobile chat app written in React Native
- Learned and utilized common development practices like Agile, TDD, and Kanban boards

ArtCenter Game Jam | ArtCenter College of Design | San Francisco, CA (Remote) Jan 2021-Mar 2021

- Collaborated with small team to design, develop, and deploy a game in 72 hours
- Produced original music and assisted lead programmers in integrating sounds into game

EDUCATION

Cornell University | BA in Italian Studies

Aug 2014-Dec 2018

- Accolades: 3.91 GPA, Dean's List 4/4 years
- Non-major studies: Computer Science, Sound Design, Physics of Musical Sound, Philosophy

RECENT EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Fleet Service Agent | American Airlines | Boston, MA

Nov 2021-present

- Coordinate with small, specialized team to complete ground services for on-time departures
- Took initiative in requesting pushback training, becoming one of a handful of employees to complete this training in their first 100 days of employment; now pushback several \$130 million aircraft every day

Archival Assistant | Jean Locey, Professional Photographer & Cornell Professor Jan 2019-Dec 2021

- Planned and executed digitization of Prof. Locey's lifelong collection of over 250 images of professional film photography work, to be archived, printed, and/or uploaded to her website
- Edited each of the 250 digital images, using Photoshop to manually adjust contrast and color balance to accurately match original finished works, to Prof. Locey's specifications